It is,
uh, July 16.
And, uh, this is a review of the current state
of the Sing for Hope and Wellbeing app.
With the end goal of this
sprint being the adaptation
and continued use of the
new phwb.singforhope.org app
in replacement with the current
system which is displayed here on the left.
The window being a google doc timesheet document.
Uh,
I will first describe this timesheet document so that we understand
what we are asking users
to move away from.
And into our new system so
that we can then therefore create a
one-to-one map of the user interface
requirements to ease in the
migration of use from the old to this new system.
So the timesheet contains
entries which represent payroll
items. So these represent,
uhm, a record of a performance by
a single artist.
In a single event.
And their calculated pay and the status of the payment.
So the first column we have is a standard date column.
Note that this timesheet displays
this column in ascending order.
Therefore, it's
not exact, but it's,
it leads to seeing the oldest records towards the
bottom of, of this sheet.
Which, by the way, we are in the FY25 sheet,
which is the only sheet we need to migrate over to
provide continuity. The second column is
the name column,
and this refers to the name of the artist.
And these names appear to be entered
from a drop-down selection of
items which represent all of the names
available of the artists. And these artist names are displayed sometimes,
or they're always displayed last name first,
comma, first name. Name, and then in parentheses,
the artist, the artistic,
or the ensemble, or the group,
or band, or organization, or contractor name,
as we can see here, there is one clear record of this.
There's a record of Suarez Paz, which is last name,
Leonardo, first name. and in.
Parentheses, LSP Productions,
and note that when this happens,
it sometimes means that this payment
record is going to reflect more
than the usual, because it will reflect payment,
not just to the artist sometime,
but also to them. Their subcontractors,
or their fellow artists that are getting paid from under this artist.
Third column we have is a location,
and this location is also a select from values,
which are color-coded. The color coatings are
blue for healing arts, yellow
for creative placemaking, gray for procedural,
and pink, or shall I say magenta for other.
We then have a list of locations,
and these are mapped into our new system as venues.
We then have column
D, which is a number column for
the number of hours. Column
E is the rate. There's a reference
to a rate card.
Which we will
dive into later. But this essentially provides
also a drop-down with values, pre-determined values.
Which are also color-coded in accordance,
I believe, to the location, which is the type.
The location is attached to a type,
like Healing Arts and Creative Placemaking,
and then that, according to the rate sheet,
dictates the pay. The rate is
in either a standard hour,
numeric amount per hour. Flat
times the number of hours, or a first
hour fee plus an additional hour fee format.
Again, we need to make a deep dive video into the rate card.
Then we have the next column.
This column is for additional pay, which this is just
entered. It's a number that's entered. We
then have addition, reason for additional pay as a column.
This also has a select with some entries,
which include Project Leader, Carthage,
Bank Deposit, Travel Expenses,
Parking, LLC, Holiday Special Guest,
Half Pay, Cancellation Fee, Band Leader,
Arts Admin, and C-Notes.
We then have a total amount,
which, column, which, uh, I believe can be computed from
the pay, calculated pay, Would you?
Is hours temp pay rate with those rules,
plus the additional pay, we can calculate this.
We then have a column for Insperity Hours,
which is meant to track the number of hours that they are accruing
on Insperity for vacation purposes.
I believe the default behavior here.
Is to copy over from the number of hours
performed. This needs to be clarified.
We then have a Date Paid column, which acts as a record
of the date that they were paid, and also as a status of whether
they have been paid or not. We
have a column for Employee slash Contractor,
which is not used, and this information,
I believe, is best tracked in the Add Artist tab.
We then have a column for Invoice Number,
and in parentheses, if applicable,
meaning that this is optional. And the
final note we have is a Notes field,
which we can analyze the content of these fields to identify
the kind of notes patterns that are
being used, and perhaps how we can build solutions,
long-term solutions. So that is a breakdown of the
current sheet, which
we need to navigate away from. And now
we will do a quick review of the
corresponding payroll page.
Which is a page that we are supposed to be modifying.
And the current state of the public health and well-being app. For context,
I'm running this app in localhost.
And we are going to be processing this video into
issues. That are going to,
To be worked on. In development.
So. I am logged in as an administrator.
The first issue. That
we need is that we need to add. In the most simple.
Uncomplicated way. We need to add.
The ability to support. User
roles. Admins. Directors and staff.
And we need for admins. To be able to add.
Other admins.
This is all done in super base. As a back end.
Then we need for admins to be able to add.
Also director users.
And staff users. And we need directors. To be able to add staff users.
Staffs cannot add any other users.
Then. We
will then have a slightly different UI
shown conditionally on permissions based on these three roles.
Administrator will always have all
permissions to do anything. Director.
Director will have most permissions to do mostly everything.
And then staff will have very limited permissions and user
interface. So they will likely show a much shorter version of this.
To keep things simple. We want to have admins have
a option to toggle
between the different views so that they can preview and experience the
application as seen and viewed by these different roles.
Then we need to add a tag on top here,
color-coded, that shows what the current view is,
so that they're aware. Having said that,
and that is the first issue that needs to be worked on,
which is more of a foundational issue,
let's continue to review the current state of the payroll tab
slash page and how it needs to be,
uhm, improved.
so the workflow here on the
left, if I want to add an entry,
it's pretty straightforward and simple and flat.
I first enter a date,
a name, you know, I go down the list essentially,
and then, uh,
Staff I do this and then every Monday or
so a director comes in Or an
admin comes in and then adds,
you know, enter processes payroll and then adds the payment dates
So The equivalent since
we don't have inline editing Directly,
but we have a drawer that allows us to edit but
the equivalent here is to click an add entry which opens the sidebar
And then enter the date the artist
The venue which is a location The event
which this is one conflict we have to work out Because there's no
such thing as an event entry in the timesheet
Multiple timesheet entries could all belong to one single event
and the workflow in this new Application
is a little different. We're not adding Timesheet
entries directly. We're supposed to be adding events out
of which timesheet entries come out of So
I'm displaying the direct at payroll entry right now Which
is gonna ask me to search and select for an event which
is not compatible with the current workflow Then
we have payment type, which I don't think it exists
on the old one Employee slash contractor
status Okay,
so this Believe one of the one of the first
other issues that needs to be worked on here immediately is
for this to turn into a
newest first on top with inline ad capabilities
that mimics very much the current time sheet so that I can then add
there's a plus button here and I can click it.
And it would add an empty row and I can go down the list
inline and simply add a new item for the payroll and
that would drastically. Adaptation
ease of use by mimicking instead of showing this conflicting
version, we now mimic.
All of the,
uhm, inline.
Then. Looking over at the events
interface, the new way of doing this would be a little different.
There would first be creation.
Creation of an event. Which requires a title in this,
perhaps this is conflicting, an event may not need a title,
it's just a date and a location,
which is a venue. Not even a program,
that comes later. And then after that, we need to go straight into artist
selection. And
make sure that these items are optimized,
this workflow. Which would create
the event. Which is not functioning
right now, this needs to be simplified,
drastically. And once we create the event,
then the event would be And then after it happened,
it would trigger automatically the creation of the corresponding payroll
entries. So that we can keep then track of their
creation by adding some sort of tagging or column.
Of whether they were created automatically by an event that happened,
or they were created manually, and then if so,
then by who. This is the first set
of issues that we need to work on to get to a stable
point of adoptability for the public health and well-being app.